Contact

+880 1521721778 (Mobile) shemantosharkarofficial@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shemanto (LinkedIn)

dev.to/shemanto_sharkar/series (Blog)

www.behance.net/shemanto27 (Other)

Top Skills

Event Management

Teamwork

Creative Problem Solving

Certifications

Introduction To Business Analytics Intermediate Python

Entrepreneurship Journey: 3 Days Long Workshop

Succeed In Business Case Competitions

Data Science

Honors-Awards

3rd in All Bangladesh Asteroid Search Campaign

1st Runner-Up in BizBash 2.0

4th in IEOM Society KUET Student Chapter presents Innovative Idea Contest

Champion Inter-University Innovation Idea & Project Competition-2022 arranged by FabLab KUET

Finalist in AGRIBIZ, Agriculture Based Inter-University Business Case Competition

Bidut Sharkar Shemanto

Co-founder at Bigganpur Technologies || Data Science || Machine Learning || IoT & Electronics Hobbyist

Khulna, Bangladesh

Summary

Summary

Science.

Data Enthusiast || Entrepreneur || Electronics Hobbyist

Co-founder of www.bigganpur.com

Email: shemantosharkarofficial@gmail.com

WhatsApp: +880 1521721778

Hello, I'm Bidut Sharkar Shemanto, and I'm on a data-driven journey. As a data enthusiast, I'm all about unlocking insights and creating value through data. Here's a snapshot of what I bring to the table:

Data analysis and wrangling skills with Excel, SQL, and Python. Data visualization and storytelling using Power BI. Proficiency in cloud computing with Microsoft Azure.

I've recently completed a 4-month online data science course and I'm actively diving into machine learning and deep learning through courses and books. My future plan? Pursuing higher studies in Data

Beyond data, I'm also an electronics hobbyist and IoT enthusiast. I love building cool electronic projects and have successfully run Bigganpur.com, my electronics venture. Automated the business, optimized processes, achieved profitability, and successfully sold products worth 3 lakh+ exclusively within KUET.

In addition to my technical proficiency in the field of data, I have learned a diverse set of skills through practical experiences in clubs, competitions, and my entrepreneurial journey. I assess my skills as follows:

#Web Designing & Development: WordPress website development and SEO #9/10

#Presentation: Microsoft PowerPoint, Excel, Canva #8.5/10

#Social Media Management: Meta Marketing, including page management and creating engaging posts #7/10 #Graphics Designing (My Portfolio: https://www.behance.net/shemanto27): Adobe Illustrator, Canva, Figma #7.5/10 #Video Editing: Filmora, CapCut, Canva #5/10

In my free time, I am exploring the field of Product Management out of sheer curiosity.

If you share my passion for data or business development, let's connect! I'm always up for friendly discussions and collaborations.

Experience

Bigganpur Technologies Ltd. Co-Founder April 2022 - Present (2 years 4 months) Bangladesh

Bigganpur.com: Empowering Electronics Enthusiasts in Bangladesh

Bigganpur.com is your one-stop destination for all things electronics, robotics, and IoT components.

What We Offer:

Electronics: We provide a wide range of electronic components, from resistors to microcontrollers, to support your projects and experiments.

Robotics: For enthusiasts and engineers looking to dive into the world of robotics, we offer an array of robotics kits and components to help bring your creations to life.

IoT (Internet of Things): Stay at the forefront of IoT with our collection of IoT components and sensors, enabling you to build smart and connected devices.

Where to Find Us:

Visit our page at www.facebook.com/bigganpur for updates and exclusive deals.

Serving the KUET Community:

We've proudly partnered with the KUET community by establishing a presence in the KUET campus, making it easy for students to access our products and place orders. Our mission is to support the academic and innovative pursuits of the bright minds at KUET.

Greater Mymensingh Association, KUET General Secretary January 2024 - Present (7 months)

KUET Business and Entrepreneurship Club

1 year 7 months

Senior Executive: Public Relations(PR) March 2023 - September 2023 (7 months)

Junior Executive: Graphics and Content Team March 2022 - April 2023 (1 year 2 months) Khulna, Bangladesh

Successfully organized KBEC PRESENTS: CASE CRACK WORKSHOP 2022 as a junior executive. I was part of the P&D squad, designing team for the event

KRIoTIC(KUET Robotics and IoT Innovation Club) General Member May 2022 - March 2023 (11 months)

HULT PRIZE at KUET
Organizing Member
September 2022 - February 2023 (6 months)

TEDx KUET

Organizing Member of TEDx KUET July 2022 - November 2022 (5 months)

TEDx is an idea-sharing event where people are invited to share their innovative ideas, inventions, and thoughts. It is a global event that has been taking place in different countries around the globe and our country as well. But for the first time ever, KUET is going to hold this prestigious event.

I worked in the graphics team and content writing team for social media posts. Before the main event, we organized a free offline campus game event: TEDxU, which was unique to other TEDx events organized by other campuses. I worked with the planning team

www.shemantosharkar.com

Blogger

January 2021 - September 2022 (1 year 9 months)

Personal Blog, where I write on skilled I learned-coding, designing, digital marketing and other stuffs. Technically I am writing here to combine my writing together in a platform and then publish as book.

Digital products, affiliate link and services are my ways to generate income from this website.

Don't forget to subscribe to my newsletter!!

Education

Khulna University of Engineering and Technology

BSc. Engineering, Energy Science and Engineering (ESE) · (2019)